Andrew M. Kent

CONTACT Information Lindley Hall 215 E-mail: andmkent@iu.edu
Indiana University Fax: (812) 855-4829

150 S. Woodlawn Ave. Github: github.com/pnwamk
Bloomington, IN 47405 WWW: pnwamk.github.io

RESEARCH INTERESTS I am interested in developing programming language based techniques that help developers design and build robust software in real world settings. In particular, I am interested in making advanced type-theoretic verification and design techniques more accessible to developers of all levels.

SKILLS

Research in programming language theory and formal logic, functional and imperative programming, experience with the Unix environment and a variety of programming languages/tools (Racket, Coq, C/C++, Agda, Java, Python, git, etc).

EDUCATION

Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana USA

Ph.D. Student, Computer Science, May 2014 - Present

GPA: 3.867

Advisor: Sam Tobin-Hochstadt

Brigham Young University, Provo, Utah USA

B.S., Computer Science, graduated magna cum laude, August 2013

PUBLICATIONS

Occurrence Typing Modulo Theories, with David Kempe and Sam Tobin-Hochstadt, *Proc.* 37th ACM Conference on Programming Language Design and Implementation (PLDI), 2016. Included successfully evaluated artifact.

Design and Evaluation of Gradual Typing in Python, with Michael M. Vitousek, Jeremy G. Siek, and Jim Baker, $Proc.~10^{th}~ACM~Symposium~on~Dynamic~Languages~(DLS),~2014.$

Linking the Past: Discovering Historical Social Networks from Documents and Linking to a Genealogical Database, with Douglas J. Kennard and William A. Barrett, *Proc.* 1st Workshop on Historical Document Imaging and Processing (HIP), 2011.

ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana USA

Graduate Research Assistant

May 2014 – Present

Investigating type-based program verification, evaluating gradual typing applications in mainstream languages, and developing techniques to bring dependent types to dynamically typed languages. Advised by Sam Tobin-Hochstadt.

 $Assistant\ Instructor$

January 2016 - Present

CSCI-B 522 and CSCI-B 401

Assisted with instruction and grading for a graduate level programming language theory course and an undergraduate level course on the theory of computation.

Brigham Young University, Provo, Utah USA

Graduate Research Assistant

August 2013 – April 2014

Investigated the formalization of security protocol analysis techniques (Strand Spaces) utilizing the Coq proof assistant to create a verified basis for accessible, automated protocol analysis techniques. Advised by Jay McCarthy.

Undergraduate Research Assistant

May - September 2011

Developed method for automatically generating historical social networks from source documents to aid historical research. Advised by William Berret and Tom Sederberg.

Talks

Practical Dependently Typed Racket, RacketCon 2015, St. Louis, MO, USA.

Adding Practical Dependent Types to Typed Racket, Scripts to Programs Workshop 2015, Prague, Czech Republic.

Professional Experience

Microsoft Corporation, Redmond, Washington USA

Software Development Engineer Intern

May 2012 - August 2012

Explored optimizations and improvements for Microsoft OneNote during a summer internship, receiving a full-time offer for employment upon completion.

United States Marine Corps, Camp Pendleton, California USA

Signals Intelligence Analyst

November 2005 - August 2010

Provided detailed signals intelligence analysis and reporting in support combat operations in the Al Anbar province of Iraq during two separate deployments. Additionally, trained and led a team of six signals intelligence analysts during the second deployment to Iraq.

OPEN SOURCE

Racket and Typed Racket

2014 – **Present**

INVOLVEMENT Contributions to the Racket programming language, especially Typed Racket.

COMMUNITY

 $Cub\ Master$

December 2014 – Present

Help organize combined scouting activities for youth ages 8-11.

Interfaith Winter Shelter Volunteer

January 2016 - Present

Evening shift volunteer for at a low-barrier winter homeless shelter.